<resources>
    <string name="app_name">DIU</string>
    <string name="app_title">Dhaka International University</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Dhaka International University</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">Student Portal</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!--<string name="menu_home">Home</string>-->
    <!--<string name="menu_gallery">Gallery</string>-->
    <string name="menu_slideshow">Slideshow</string>

    <string name="menu_share">Share</string>
    <string name="menu_send">Send</string>


    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_class_routine">Class Routine</string>
    <string name="menu_notice">Notice Board</string>
    <string name="menu_accounts">Account Details</string>
    <string name="menu_result">Academic Result</string>
    <string name="menu_academic_calender">Academic Calendar</string>


    <string name="menu_administration">Administration</string>
    <string name="menu_faculity_member">Board of Trustee</string>
    <string name="menu_student_comunity">Students Community</string>
    <string name="menu_transport">Transport</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Photo Gallery</string>


    <string name="menu_faq">FAQ</string>
    <string name="menu_rules_regulation">Rules and Regulations</string>
    <string name="menu_exam_guidline">Examination Guideline</string>
    <string name="menu_credit_transfer">Credit Accept/Transfer</string>
    <string name="menu_admission">Admission</string>
    <string name="menu_depertment">Departments</string>
    <string name="menu_contact">Contact</string>


    <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="menu_about">About</string>
    <string name="text_admission_req">For Undergraduate/ Honors Program:

\n> Original Transcript \u0026 Certificate of S.S.C. or Equivalent with 2 photocopies.
\n> Original Transcript \u0026 Certificate of H.S.C. or Equivalent with 2 photocopies.
\n> 7 Copies of Pass Port size Photograph .
\n> For Master’s / Graduate Program:
\n> Original Transcript \u0026 Certificate of S.S.C. or Equivalent with 2 photocopies.
\n> Original Transcript \u0026 Certificate of H.S.C. or Equivalent with 2 photocopies.
\n> Original Transcript \u0026 Certificate of Undergraduate/ Honor’s Program with 2 photocopies.
\n> 7 Copies of Pass Port size Photograph .</string>


    <string name="text_admission">Candidates seeking admission must apply in prescribed application Form which can be collected on payment of Tk. 1000.00 Candidates having 2nd division or at least GPA 2.50 in both SSC \u0026 HSC examinations, or their equivalents are eligible to apply for admission into Honours program in Law,English, Sociology and Business Administration. For B.Sc in (Computer Science u0026 Engineering), B.Sc.( Electrical, Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering) and B.Sc (Civil Engineering) programs, candidate must have physics \u0026 Mathematics at their HSC level.For Bachelor of Pharmacy (B.Pharm.) program, candidates must have Biology \u0026 Chemistry at their HSC level.For LL.M (2 years), M.A English (2.5 Years), MSS Sociology (2 Years), MHRL, and MBA programs, the applicants must have at least Bachelor Degree with GPA-2.00 (minimum). For LL.M (2 Years), student must complete LL.B (Pass) Course.</string>
    <string name="text_about">Dhaka International University (DIU) is one of the leading, familiar and note-worthy private universities in Bangladesh which was established on 7th April 1995. It is a non-profitable institution having strict academic discipline. This university was founded by Late Alhaj Professor Dr. A. B. M. Mafizul Islam Patwari, Former Chairman of the Department of Law, University of Dhaka, Bangladesh. It is recognized that Dhaka International University is such a private university, which was founded by a person who was a renowned humanist and academician. He established this university with high hopes and aspirations to disseminate knowledge and thus to extend the horizon of knowledge. That is why, the motto of DIU is the universal adage, "Knowledge is Power". DIU generates this power of Knowledge in an individual through teaching-learning, training, research and guidance by using modern, pragmatic and well-designed curriculum and syllabus.</string>
    <string name="text_mission">The mission of DIU is to produce capable leaders in the respective field of study who can meet the challenges of present dynamic world. It wants to create multidisciplinary knowledge, communication and interpersonal skills at the highest level of excellence among the students which will make them honest, sincere and dedicated in their thoughts and deeds.</string>
    <string name="text_vission">The vision of DIU is to contribute to the nation by producing age-worthy, pragmatic and eligible graduates through continual innovation in education and research.</string>


    <string name="dept_business_introduction">The University Grants Commission of Bangladesh (UGC) was established by the Presidential Order (P.O. No 10 of 1973) of the Government of the People\’s Republic of Bangladesh. In fact, UGC is the regulatory body of all public and private universities in Bangladesh. Three categories of university such as public, private and international universities are working to ensure higher education in Bangladesh.

\n \n In Bangladesh, private university started its journey after the constitution of the Private University Act 1992. At present, all private universities are being operated under the Private University Act 2010. There are 95 private universities in Bangladesh (up to January, 2017). Dhaka International University is one of the first generation private universities in Bangladesh.
</string>
    <string name="dept_business_mission">To educate students in a communicative and interactive learning environment in line with program outcomes and to empower them to meet the business challenges with strong ethical values and responsibilities.</string>
    <string name="dept_business_vission">To produce eligible and competent business graduates through a standard curriculum who will be able to serve the society as business leaders in the global perspective.</string>


    <string name="dept_civil_introduction">The Department of Civil Engineering is one of the largest department in the Faculty of Science \u0026 Engineering. The department has produced several eminent engineers who have made important contributions in the planning and execution of many important Civil Engineering projects in Bangladesh as well as abroad.

\n\nThe Department offers two shift (Day and Ev ening) undergraduate courses in Civil Engineering. In all, there are around 1000 students , including I nternational students, in undergraduate program for pursuing their Bachelor degree. The Department is known for its reputed faculty with expertise in dive rse fields. Presently, the department has 20 highly qualified, experienced, sincere and dedicated teaching faculty members, actively participating in research and consultancy work. During last 5 years, faculty members have published more than 2 0 papers in reputed refereed International Journals.
\n\nOver a period of time, the Department has built up a wide research potential.Major area of research in the Department include; Sustainable Development, low cost sanitation, water treatment, air, noise and water qua lity modelling, Reuse of concrete, application of GIS and remote sensing in water resources and environment, Vulnerability assessment, Seismic analysis of structures, retrofitting, Soil structure interaction, Hydro - climatology, Water resource assessment an d management.
\n\nThe Department has established a state of the art experimental facilities and laboratories in different fields of Civil Engineering. International and national conferences, seminars and special lectures are a regular feature of the Department to impart education and training. Leading companies in construction sector in Bangladesh and public divisions are regular recruiter of our students and many students have been selected in Engineering Services.
\n\nThe Department strongly believes in continuous efforts to strive for excellence by exploring new frontiers of knowledge, imparting the latest technical knowledge to the students and conducting high quality research.
</string>
    <string name="dept_civil_mission">--> To offer Under - Graduate and Post - Graduate programs in civil engineering and other skill development courses that add value to student competencies.
\n\n--> To establish centers of excellence in emerging areas of research.
\n\n--> To promote innovative and original thinking in the minds of budding engineers to face the challenges of future .
\n\n--> To have regular interaction with industry and offer solutions to their problems.
\n\n--> To provide knowledge base and consu ltancy services to the community in all areas of civil engineering.
\n\n--> To introduce moral and ethical values among the students
</string>
    <string name="dept_civil_vission">To acquaint knowledge and excellence that brings out to our graduates with high technical competencies and promotes hig h - end research which m akes them ethically strong engineers to build our nation.</string>

    <string name="dept_cse_introduction">The Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) at Dhaka International University (also known as DIU) is a place where brightest minds from all over the country and abroad assembles for a greater future. We have a strong alumni association to exchange academic and professional knowledge and experience among the existing and former students of DIU in the field of CSE. Our alumni serve in the top ranking universities as teachers and researchers and in the top companies all around the world as software engineers and IT specialists. We organize various co-curricular and extra-curriculum activities. Such as Programming contest, Workshop, job Fair, The Debating Club, Seminar, Intra-Department Football/Cricket Tournament, Indoor Games, etc. Our students are well equipped to take the challenge to stand out as the leaders of tomorrow. We welcome all in our community who are willing to take the challenge and who are trying to be the best in their future. Welcome to CSEDIU.</string>
    <string name="dept_cse_mission">The mission of department of computer Science and Engineering (CSE) is to teach and prepare educated, skilled, \u0026 ethically sound computer scientists and engineers for leadership and professional careers and for advanced studies.</string>
    <string name="dept_cse_vission">To produce competent professionals who shall be leaders in technology, industry and research at the national and international level.</string>

    <string name="dept_eete_introduction">Electrical, Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering (EETE) education today has entered a transitional phase. EETE curricula around the globe are increasing specialization. On the other hand, diversity of EETE education is also increasingly underscoring its multi-disciplinary nature. Over the last decade, the traditional role played by an electrical and electronics engineer has changed quite significantly. Today\’s employers require electrical, electronics and telecommunication engineers with excellent communication skills along with awareness about environmental and safety issues. There are huge demand for electrical, electronics and telecommunication profession but the supply of technical competent professionals in Bangladesh is not meeting the demand. The B.Sc. degree program in Electrical, Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering at Dhaka International University (DIU) is aimed to produce graduates to meet that demand. Increasing the ethical and moral standards of the engineers is also getting higher priority in the industry and communication technology sector.</string>
    <string name="dept_eete_mission">The mission of the department is to teach and prepare educated, articulated and skilled engineers for leadership, professional careers and advanced studies in the field of Electrical and Electronics engineering.</string>
    <string name="dept_eete_vission">To produce competent professionals who will be leaders in technology, industry and research at national and international levels.</string>

    <string name="dept_english_introduction">Department of English is one of the two departments of the Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences established in 1995-1996 session with a view to producing competent and efficient graduate and postgraduate students. There are three ongoing programs under this department: Bachelor of Arts (Hons) in English (Day \u0026 Evening), Master of Arts in English (One year), and Master of Arts in English (Two \u0026 half years). BA (Hons) program is running under trimester system. Both the MA programs are following bi-semester system. This department generally aims at providing students with exposure to the areas and aspects of English language, literature and cultural studies. It specifically seeks to further refine students\’ sensibilities, sharpen their critical faculty and equip them with the knowledge and skills that will make them qualified and capable persons for the challenging world. English literature degree programs center on the literature of the Anglophone world. In an English literature program, students learn about the history and structure of the English language and linguistics, develop their writing and rhetoric skills and study the literary genius including William Shakespeare, John Milton, Herman Melville, William Wordsworth, Chinua Achebe and many more. The degree involves reading many types of dramas, novels, short stories, essays and poems. Students who have earned a degree in English literature might end up working in diversified careers home and abroad within academic circles and beyond.</string>
    <string name="dept_english_mission">Department of English aims at the liberal education of students by developing a deepened understanding of language and literacy, the value of critical reading and effective writing, and the richness of literature, past and present.</string>
    <string name="dept_english_vission">We seek to foster knowledge and a love of literature and of language in our students. To this end we will provide students with a coherent curricular framework, well-structured courses. We will teach a variety of literary, analytical, pedagogical, and theoretical skills. We will teach students to speak, read, and write effectively. We will encourage students to think deeply and to reflect on what they have learned. We will encourage a love of learning and an appreciation for an education of autonomy.</string>

    <string name="dept_law_introduction">Dhaka International University Faculty of Law is one of the preeminent centers of legal education in Bangladesh. Founded by prominent jurist, humanist and former chairman of Department of Law, University of Dhaka Late Alhaj Professor Dr. A B M Mafizul Islam Patwari, this faculty is the first legal education provider among all private universities in Bangladesh. Led by a diverse and dedicated group of faculty, legal scholars, researchers and practitioners, Faculty of Law provides unmatched opportunities of excellence and educational intimacy to study law and related disciplines in a rigorous and collaborative environment.
        \n\nThe faculty\’s curriculum is unparalleled in its breadth and depth to cope up with the present demand. For students, the experience is unparalleled. The faculty-student ratio supports a vast array of courses and opportunities for independent research and student-organized seminars. Students get practical training from clinical legal education, moot court, mock trial, court visit and other activities.
        \n\nThe faculty of law founded in 1995 as one of the leading research and teaching law school with 4 years Bachelor of Laws (LL.B.) (Hons), Master of Laws (LL.M.) (1 \u0026 2 Years) and Master of Human Rights Laws (MHRL) (2 Years) programmes. DIU Faculty of Law offers students and alumni resources supporting both public and private careers. The faculty\’s network of distinguished alumni spans the globe.
\n\nDIU Law Faculty is unique among law schools in that it produces leaders in all walks of life: distinguished faculty members at law schools across the country; industry CEOs and corporate counsels; nongovernmental organizations and other nonprofit entities; entrepreneurs; government servants and the judiciary — just a few areas in which our alumni\’s talent and passion and dedication have made a difference. So, wherever you hope your future will lead, our Law Faculty can help you get there.
</string>
    <string name="dept_law_mission">--> The department of law prepares students to become excellent human resource with a high degree of professional skills and a special sensitivity to ethical and moral concerns. We serve society locally, nationally and internationally by providing a collaborative environment in which to learn, think, and communicate about law, policy and justice. Our teaching method is designed to teach students about the law and to develop their skills necessary to use that knowledge in practice. Our mission also includes:

\n\nProducing skilled law graduates
\n--> Prepare the students to become professional in effective communication, course of professional practices, teamwork and leadership skill.
\n--> Espousing the virtues of truth, integrity, honesty, tolerance, professionalism, teamwork and meritocracy.
\n--> Upholding the ethics and etiquette of legal professions.
\n--> Provide graduates for becoming successful entrepreneur in legal profession.
\n--> Endeavor to produce jurists who are capable of lateral and critical thinking, able to serve the country and its entire people.
</string>
    <string name="dept_law_vission">The vision of the faculty of law is to advance human dignity, social welfare, promoting justice through excellent teaching, research and service to all branches of the legal community in local and global society.</string>

    <string name="dept_pharmecy_introduction">The Department of Pharmacy is one of the best \u0026 demandful department in the Faculty of Science \u0026 Engineering at present. The department has produced several eminent pharmacist who have made important contributions in the pharmaceutical companies and products many important medicine in the pharmaceutical companies of Bangladesh as well as abroad.
        \n\nThe Dhaka International University (also known as DIU) launched the educational activities of the Department of Pharmacy from January 2006 under the Faculty of Science and Engineering. Presently, the department has some highly qualified, experienced, sincere and dedicated teaching faculty members, actively participating in research work. Bachelor of Pharmacy. B. Pharm (Hons.) program is running under bi-semester system. The Department aims at providing students with exposure to the areas and aspects of professional degree of pharmacy. It specifically seeks to further fine students\’ sensibilities, sharpens their critical faculty and equips them with the knowledge and skills that will make them qualified and capable persons. B. Pharm (Hons.) program at DIU tries to give the students not only the theoretical basis but also the practical and industrial knowledge compulsory for them. Our vision is to create leaders of Pharmaceutical Sciences.
</string>
    <string name="dept_pharmecy_mission">The mission is to build up professional experts on drugs to meet the demands of the age in the field of pharmacy.</string>
    <string name="dept_pharmecy_vission">Our vision is to create leaders of Pharmaceutical Sciences.</string>

    <string name="dept_sociology_introduction">Sociology, a scholarly discipline aims at understanding and exploring the origin, development, organization and functioning of human society. Being a multi-disciplinary approach, this program launches to lead and equip students with the fundamental and applied principle of sociology, which is the positive science of society. As a scientific discipline, sociology poses for showing the nexus between theory and data to make sense of the social problems clearly in a systematic manner. Emerging in the middle of 19th century, Sociology dominates extensively for building global leaders, policy makers and young professionals all over the world with a view to inspiring and implementing several development initiatives. Eventually, this discipline has amazingly articulated ample opportunities and created new avenues for welcoming diversified professions in a challenging environment. Department of Sociology is one of the leading Departments of Dhaka International University. It started the journey in 1996. Two shifts are concurrently run here as B.S.S program: Day shift and Evening Shift. At the current stage, 32nd batch is running in both Day shift and Evening shift. Department also provides M.S.S. degree (both one and two years).The former students of Sociology Department have formed DIU Sociology Alumni Association. This has created an opportunity to exchange academic and professional knowledge and experience among the existing and former students of Dhaka International University in the field of Sociology.</string>
    <string name="dept_sociology_mission">Ensuring global standards of multidisciplinary teaching through skilled faculty members.
\nPromoting multi-pluralistic knowledge generation in sociological setting.
</string>
    <string name="dept_sociology_vission">Building potential leaders and professionals in global setting.</string>

    <string name="dept_economics_introduction">The Department of Economics is one of the largest department in the Faculty of Science \u0026 Engineering. The department has produced several eminent engineers who have made important contributions in the planning and execution of many important Economics projects in Bangladesh as well as abroad.
        \n\nThe Department offers two shift (Day and Ev ening) undergraduate courses in Economics. In all, there are around 1000 students , including I nternational students, in undergraduate program for pursuing their Bachelor degree. The Department is known for its reputed faculty with expertise in dive rse fields. Presently, the department has 20 highly qualified, experienced, sincere and dedicated teaching faculty members, actively participating in research and consultancy work. During last 5 years, faculty members have published more than 2 0 papers in reputed refereed International Journals.
        \n\nOver a period of time, the Department has built up a wide research potential.Major area of research in the Department include; Sustainable Development, low cost sanitation, water treatment, air, noise and water qua lity modelling, Reuse of concrete, application of GIS and remote sensing in water resources and environment, Vulnerability assessment, Seismic analysis of structures, retrofitting, Soil structure interaction, Hydro - climatology, Water resource assessment an d management.
        \n\nThe Department has established a state of the art experimental facilities and laboratories in different fields of Economics. International and national conferences, seminars and special lectures are a regular feature of the Department to impart education and training. Leading companies in construction sector in Bangladesh and public divisions are regular recruiter of our students and many students have been selected in Engineering Services.
\n\nThe Department strongly believes in continuous efforts to strive for excellence by exploring new frontiers of knowledge, imparting the latest technical knowledge to the students and conducting high quality research.
</string>
    <string name="dept_economics_mission">--> To offer Under - Graduate and Post - Graduate programs in civil engineering and other skill development courses that add value to student competencies.
--> To establish centers of excellence in emerging areas of research.
--> To promote innovative and original thinking in the minds of budding engineers to face the challenges of future .
--> To have regular interaction with industry and offer solutions to their problems.
--> To provide knowledge base and consu ltancy services to the community in all areas of civil engineering.
--> To introduce moral and ethical values among the students
</string>
    <string name="dept_economics_vission">To acquaint knowledge and excellence that brings out to our graduates with high technical competencies and promotes hig h - end research which m akes them ethically strong engineers to build our nation.</string>

    <string name="dept_political_science_introduction">The Department of Political science is one of the largest department in the Faculty of Science \u0026 Engineering. The department has produced several eminent engineers who have made important contributions in the planning and execution of many important Political science projects in Bangladesh as well as abroad.
\n\nThe Department offers two shift (Day and Ev ening) undergraduate courses in Political science. In all, there are around 1000 students , including I nternational students, in undergraduate program for pursuing their Bachelor degree. The Department is known for its reputed faculty with expertise in dive rse fields. Presently, the department has 20 highly qualified, experienced, sincere and dedicated teaching faculty members, actively participating in research and consultancy work. During last 5 years, faculty members have published more than 2 0 papers in reputed refereed International Journals.
\n\nOver a period of time, the Department has built up a wide research potential.Major area of research in the Department include; Sustainable Development, low cost sanitation, water treatment, air, noise and water qua lity modelling, Reuse of concrete, application of GIS and remote sensing in water resources and environment, Vulnerability assessment, Seismic analysis of structures, retrofitting, Soil structure interaction, Hydro - climatology, Water resource assessment an d management.
\n\nThe Department has established a state of the art experimental facilities and laboratories in different fields of Political science. International and national conferences, seminars and special lectures are a regular feature of the Department to impart education and training. Leading companies in construction sector in Bangladesh and public divisions are regular recruiter of our students and many students have been selected in Engineering Services.
\n\nThe Department strongly believes in continuous efforts to strive for excellence by exploring new frontiers of knowledge, imparting the latest technical knowledge to the students and conducting high quality research.
</string>
    <string name="dept_political_science_mission">--> To offer Under - Graduate and Post - Graduate programs in civil engineering and other skill development courses that add value to student competencies.
--> To establish centers of excellence in emerging areas of research.
--> To promote innovative and original thinking in the minds of budding engineers to face the challenges of future .
--> To have regular interaction with industry and offer solutions to their problems.
--> To provide knowledge base and consu ltancy services to the community in all areas of civil engineering.
--> To introduce moral and ethical values among the students
</string>
    <string name="dept_political_science_vission">To acquaint knowledge and excellence that brings out to our graduates with high technical competencies and promotes hig h - end research which m akes them ethically strong engineers to build our nation.</string>





    <string name="club_cpc_introduction">DIU Computer and Programming Club (DIU CPC) is one of the largest and popular club of Dhaka International University which is established on 2014. Currently it has 150 registered members. DIU CPC arranges different different kind of even in every year. One hundred plus students are learning programming under the students skill development project(SSDP) of DIU CPC.</string>
    <string name="club_cpc_mission">The mission of DIU CPC is making skillful IT person who can meet the challenge of present world. And create, share, and apply knowledge in Computer Science.</string>
    <string name="club_cpc_vision">The vision of DIU CPC is helping students to enrich their knowledge of computer and programming.</string>
    <string name="club_cpc_registration">Usualy CPC takes mamber in the month of January, May, October. Registration fee is 100/- BDT.</string>


</resources>
